上一节课中 我们学习了指数加权平均
In the last video, we talked about
exponentially weighted averages.
这将是几个训练神经网络的优化算法的
This will turn out to be a key component of
关键组成部分
several optimization algorithms
that you used to train your neural networks.
所以 在这个视频中 我将详细讲解
So, in this video, I want to delve a little bit deeper
这一算法的具体作用
into intuitions for what this algorithm is really doing.
先回顾一下 这是实现指数加权平均的关键等式。
Recall that this is a key equation
for implementing exponentially weighted averages.
如果β=0.9 可以获得红色曲线
And so, if β=0.9, you got the red line.
如果β值趋向于1
If it was much closer to one,
如果β=0.98 可以获得绿色曲线
if it was 0.98, you get the green line.
如果数值更小
And if it's much smaller,
比如0.5 可以获得黄色曲线
maybe 0.5, you get the yellow line.
接下来我们来了解下
Let's look a bit more than that to understand how
它是如何计算每日气温的
this is computing averages of the daily temperature.
这是运算等式
So, here's that equation again.
假设β=0.9 我们来列出相应的等式
and let's set beta equals 0.9 and write out
a few equations that this corresponds to.
因此 当运算时 你的T值
So whereas, when you're implementing it you have T
从0到1 到2 到3
going from zero to one, to two, to three,
T值逐渐增大 为了方便分析
increasing values of T. To analyze it,
我将T值按降序排列 这里只列出一部分
I've written it with decreasing values of T.
And this goes on.
我们先以第一个等式为例
So let's take this first equation here,
了解下V100到底是什么
and understand what V100 really is.
V100将是
So V100 is going to be,
先将这两项互换一下
let me reverse these two terms,
这项变成0.1*θ100
this is going to be 0.1 times theta 100,
加上0.9乘以前一天的数值
plus 0.9 times whatever the value was
on the previous day.
那么 V99又是什么
Now, but what is V99?
我们把它代入这个等式
Well, we'll just plug it in from this equation.
所以V99就等于0.1*θ99
So this is just going to be 0.1 times theta 99,
当然 这两项也被互换了
and again I've reversed these two terms,
加上0.9*V98
plus 0.9 times V98.
那么 V98又是什么
But then what is V98?
你可以从这个等式中得知
Well, you just get that from here.
你可以代入这里
So you can just plug in here,
0.1*θ98
0.1 times theta 98,
加上0.9*V97,以此类推
plus 0.9 times V97, and so on.
如果将这些项全部相乘
And if you multiply all of these terms out,
能得到V100=0.1*θ100加上
you can show that V100 is 0.1 times theta 100 plus.
现在 我们看下θ99的系数
Now, let's look at the coefficient on theta 99,
将是0.1*0.9*θ99
it's going to be 0.1 times 0.9, times theta 99.
现在 我们看下θ98的系数
Now, let's look at the coefficient on theta 98,
为0.1*0.9*0.9
there's a 0.1 here times 0.9, times 0.9.
所以 如果我们展开代数
So if we expand out the Algebra,
这就是0.1*0.9²*θ98
this become 0.1 times 0.9 squared, times theta 98.
如果你继续展开
And, if you keep expanding this out,
这一项将变成0.1*0.9³
you find that this becomes 0.1 times 0.9 cubed,
*θ97+0.1
(times) theta97 plus 0.1.
乘以0.9的四次方
times 0.9 to the fourth,
乘以θ96 加上点点点
times theta 96, plus dot dot dot.
这是一种求和方式 也是θ100的加权平均值
So this is really a way to sum and
that's a weighted average of theta 100,
是目前的每日气温
which is the current days temperature and
we're looking for
也是我们对第一百天的气温的预估
a perspective of V100 which you calculate
on the 100th day of the year.
但这些是 θ100
But those are sum of your theta 100,
θ99 θ98
theta 99, theta 98,
θ97 θ96等等的总和
theta 97, theta 96, and so on.
所以 一种画图方法可以是
So one way to draw this in pictures would be if,
假设 我们有几天的气温值
let's say we have some number of days of temperature
这是θ 这是T θ100是一个总和值
So this is theta and this is T.
So theta 100 will be sum value,
θ99也是一个总和值
then theta 99 will be sum value,
θ98 以及这些
theta 98, so these are,
这是T=100
so this is T equals 100,
(t等于) 99 98 诸如此类
99, 98, and so on,
每日气温和总和之间的比率
ratio of sum number of days of temperature.
接着 我们能得到一个指数衰减函数
And what we have is then
an exponentially decaying function.
起止点为0.1和0.9
So starting from 0.1 to 0.9,
乘以0.1 (乘以)0.9²
times 0.1 to 0.9 squared,
乘以0.1 然后依次类推
times 0.1, to and so on.
这就是指数衰减函数
So you have this exponentially decaying function.
你计算V100的方式
And the way you compute V100,
就是选择两个函数间的元素 然后求和
is you take the element wise product
between these two functions and sum it up.
例如 选这个值
So you take this value,
θ100*0.1
theta 100 times 0.1,
乘以这个值 θ99*0.1*0.9
times this value of theta 99 times 0.1 times 0.9,
这是第二项 依次类推
that's the second term and so on.
这将每日气温值
So it's really taking the daily temperature,
乘以这个指数衰减函数 然后求和
multiply with this exponentially decaying function,
and then summing it up.
这就是你的V100值
And this becomes your V100.
事实证明 使用链式法则来计算
具体细节 我们稍后再讲
up to details that we will talk about later，
但这里的所有系数
but all of these coefficients,
加起来等于1或接近1
add up to one or add up to very close to one
将涉及我们下一讲中的偏差修正
up to a detail called bias correction
which we'll talk about in the next video.
但正因为如此 这的确是一个指数加权平均值
But because of that,
this really is an exponentially weighted average.
最后 你可能会想
And finally, you might wonder,
这是几天的平均气温值
how many days temperature is this averaging over.
结果是0.9的十次方
Well, it turns out that 0.9 to the power of 10,
大约0.35 也就是大约1/E
is about 0.35 and
this turns out to be about one over E,
一个自然算法的基础值
one of the base of natural algorithms.
通常 如果有1-ε
And, more generally, if you have one minus epsilon,
以此为例
so in this example,
ε=0.1
epsilon would be 0.1,
因此 (1-ε)的1/ε方
so if this was 0.9,
then one minus epsilon to the one over epsilon.
大约是1/E
This is about one over E,
大约是0.34 0.35
this is about 0.34, 0.35.
换句话说
And so, in other words,
大约需要10天
it takes about 10 days for the height of this to
这一值能降到峰值1/E的1/3
decay to around 1/3 already one over E of the peak.
正因为此
So it's because of this,
当β=0.9 我们说
that when beta equals 0.9, we say that,
就好像你在计算时
this is as if you're computing,
指数加权平均值只关注最近十天的气温值
an exponentially weighted average that
focuses on just the last 10 days temperature.
因为十天后 气温值将降至
Because it's after 10 days that the weight decays
不到目前气温值的三分之一
to less than about
a third of the weight of the current day.
相反 如果β=0.98
Whereas, in contrast, if beta was equal to 0.98,
那0.98的几次方才能使这个值足够小
then, well, what do you need 0.98 to the power of
in order for this to really small?
结果 0.98的50次方大约
Turns out that 0.98 to the power of 50
will be approximately
等于1/E 所以 要使数值足够大
equal to one over E. So the way to be pretty big
头五十天的数值必须远大于1/E
will be bigger than one over E for the first 50 days,
之后 它们将会很快衰减
and then they'll decay quite rapidly over that.
所以 感觉上这是一件困难又迅速的事
So intuitively, this is the hard and fast thing,
你可以把它看作50天的平均气温
you can think of this as averaging over
about 50 days temperature.
因为在这个例子中
Because, in this example,
要使用等式左边的这一项
to use the notation here on the left,
ε需要等于0.02
it's as if epsilon is equal to 0.02,
1/ε等于50
so one over epsilon is 50.
顺便说一下 我们也就是这样获得这个公式的
And this, by the way, is how we got the formula,
我们获得1/(1-β)或相应天数的平均值
that we averaging over one over one minus beta
or so days.
在这里 ε可替换1-β
Right here, epsilon replace a row of 1 minus beta.
它能告诉你 大概多少天的气温值
It tells you, up to some constant roughly how many
可以作为气温均值
days' temperature you should think of this
as averaging over.
但这只是一种经验之谈
But this is just a rule of thumb for
how to think about it,
并非正式的数学表述方式
and it isn't a formal mathematical statement.
最后 我们来了解下 如何在实际情况中使用它
Finally, let's talk about
how you actually implement this.
回顾下 我们先将V0设为0
Recall that we start over V0 initialized as zero,
然后 计算第一天的值V1
then compute V one on the first day,
V2，等第
V2, and so on.
现在 为了解释这一算法
Now, to explain the algorithm,
需要写下V0
it was useful to write down V0,
V1 V2 及其他数值 作为不同的变量
V1, V2, and so on as distinct variables.
但实际使用这一运算时
But if you're implementing this in practice,
这是你需要做的 初始化V值为0
this is what you do:
you initialize V to be called to zero,
第一天
and then on day one,
你将V值设为
you would set V equals beta,
β*V+(1-β)*θ1
times V, plus one minus beta, times theta one.
第二天 更新V值
And then on the next day, you will update V,
被称为
to be called to
βV+(1-β)*θ2
beta V, plus 1 minus beta,
以此类推
theta 2, and so on.
有时 我们用V下标θ来表示
And sometimes we use this notation V
subscript theta to denote that
V在计算指数加权平均值θ
V is computing this exponentially weighted average
of the parameter theta.
用四个新表达式再讲一遍
So just to say this again but with four new formats,
设置Vθ=0
you set V theta equals zero,
接着 不间断地 给每一天设置一个值
and then, repeatedly, have one each day,
你会得到θT 将它代入Vθ
you would get next theta T, and then set to V theta,
得到
gets updated as
β乘以Vθ的旧值
beta, times the old value of V theta,
加上(1-β)
plus one minus beta,
乘以Vθ的当前值
times the current value of V theta.
这个指数加权平均公式的优点之一是
So one of the advantages of
this exponentially weighted average formula,
不需要太多存储空间
is that it takes very little memory.
只需在计算机内存中保留一行数字
You just need to keep just
one row number in computer memory,
基于新数值 你用这个公式不断重写运算即可
and you keep on overwriting it with this formula
based on the latest values that you got.
主要是因为高效
And it's really this reason, the efficiency,
它基本只占一行代码
it just takes one line of code basically
一个单一初始值的储存和内存空间
and just storage and memory for
a single raw number
来计算指数加权平均值
to compute this exponentially weighted average.
这并不是最好的方法
It's really not the best way,
不是计算均值最准确的方法
not the most accurate way to compute an average.
如果你需要计算一个移动窗口
If you were to compute a moving window,
例如 直接算出近十天或五十天的气温总和
where you explicitly sum over the last 10 days,
除以10或者50
the last 50 days temperature
and just divide by 10 or divide by 50,
通常会给你一个更好的估计值
that usually gives you a better estimate.
但缺点是
But the disadvantage of that,
保存所有气温值
of explicitly keeping all the temperatures around and
以及近十天气温的总和 需要更多内存
sum of the last 10 days is it requires more memory,
更难实现 花费也更高
and it's just more complicated to implement
and is computationally more expensive.
在接下来的视频中 我们会看到一些例子
So for things,
we'll see some examples on the next few videos,
需要你计算很多变量的平均值
where you need to compute
averages of a lot of variables.
不论是计算还是存储效率 今天介绍的这个方法都十分高效
This is a very efficient way
to do so both from computation
这也是为什么它在机器学习中被广泛应用
and memory efficiency point of view
which is why it's used in a lot of machine learning.
更不用说它的另一个优势 就是只需一行代码
Not to mention that there's just one line of code
which is, maybe, another advantage.
现在 你知道了如何实现指数加权平均运算
So, now, you know how to implement
exponentially weighted averages.
另一个值得你了解的技术细节是
There's one more technical detail
that's worth for you knowing
偏差修正
about called bias correction.
我们将在下一讲中介绍 那之后
Let's see that in the next video, and then after that,
你就能用这些方法去建立
you will use this to build
一个更好的优化算法
a better optimization algorithm
than the straight forward
GTC字幕组翻译